A Guide to the American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) records FA079
Rockefeller Archive Center
- American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) photographs, 1946-1968, n.d.; 1027; 6.2 Cubic Feet 19 boxes.
  - Venezuela, 4
    - CBR, Miscellaneous, Rural Youth Club, Prints: 28 (Box 12, Folder 230)
      149. 5-V Club Members at San Francisco de Asis singing opening hymn. 150. Group of 5-V Club girls from Palo Negro dancing the Venezuelan folk dance, the Joropo. 151. Maria Hernandez, 14 year old 5-V Club president showing the complete set of bedroom furniture she constructed herself as a part of her home improvement project. 152. A student of the Escuela Practica de Agricultura in Providencia, state of Aragua, performs a vaccination on poultry as a classroom demonstration. 153. 5-V Club members are youthful teenagers, interested in cooking, sewing, gardening and improving their rural homes and helping their families. A veteran CBR worker with 5-V groups is Mrs. Lillian Fernandez, who helped organize several clubs in Barinas, when she directed the CBR home demonstration program there, and how is a consultant attached to the Training Center for Farm Home Agents. Student Farm Home agents receive training as leaders of 5-V clubs and, in their eventual field work, will be concerned with organizing and guiding these important youth units. 154. Exhibit of the clothes made by the 5-V Club Girls at San Francisco de Asis. 155. Members of 4-S clubs - modeled on the 4-H outline of the U.S. - learn to make furniture from boxes and scrap lumber. The ACAR home supervisor and local volunteer give guidance. 156. ACAR home supervisor teaches wife of a borrower how to prepare vegetables and emphasizes need for balanced meals. 157. Farm children meet with ACAR agronomist Erwin Fuchs in hybrid corn fields which they are cultivating as a 4-S project. 158. No caption. 159. Iranio Janduzzo, of the Rio Clarinho Club, at Santa Rita do Passa Quatro, who harvested 18 baskets of hybrid corn (an average of 120 ears per basket) from the 1- kg of hybrid seed corn planted on poor land. 160. No caption. 161. Air photo interpretation - air photos serve as base for making detailed maps and analyzing the land resources of areas being studied under CBR direction in southeast Venezuela. 162. No caption. 163. Farm girls learn about balanced diet by preparing healthful dishes at 4-S club meetings, under ACAR supervision. 164. Primitive kitchen - showing cooking arrangements in a rural home before being improved by housewife under guidance of CBR home management technicians. 165. Farm machinery training - showing CBR trainers and some of the trainees with farm tractors and equipment at one of the CBR mobile training centers in Yaracuy state. 166. Improved kitchen - showing better cooking facilities built under guidance of CBR home management technician. 167. A rural house - this is the type of house being replaced by self-help rural housing program of Ministry of Health with technicians trained in cooperation with CBR. 168. No caption. 169. Community Center - Cuidad Ojeda community center in Zulia state where classes in sewing, cooking, child care, house improvement are given, together withand other community activities; all developed by local community group under CBR direction. 170. Farm to market - type of road surveyed and built in Venezuela Andes with CBR technical guidance. 171. Resources studies - examples of maps prepared by CBR technicians for use in planned development of agriculture in the state of Yaracuy. 172. Andean farming - primitive wooden plow and oxen used in breaking land on steep Andean hillsides, a far cry from mechanized methods on level land. 173. Farm to market - in forested low country built by state of Portuguesa with CBR technical guidance. 174. No caption. 175. Child care - Ministry of Health doctor examines a child in MAC-CBR rural community center, one of the many center activities to help improve rural living conditions. 176. Rural housing - a campesino making pressed earth (with a little cement) blocks to build a new home, under CBR guidance.
    - CBR, Miscellaneous, Sanitation, Prints: 1 (Box 12, Folder 231)
      177. CBR staff member shows trainees how to make use of visual aids in home demonstration work.
    - CBR, Miscellaneous, Special Studies, Prints: 72 (Box 12, Folder 232)
      178. The electric microsol sprayer brings comfort to animals tormented by insects and parasites and results in happier, healthier cows, an increased milk supply and consequent gains for the dairyman. 179. Troublesome parasites are destroyed by a close-range spraying. These pests can so annoy a cow that she will lose weight, and her milk supply will be jeopardized. 180. The electric microsol sprayer is effectively employed in this dairy barn, one of the more modern installations in the area known as the Caracas milkshed. The photo was taken during a study made of the Caracas dairy supply area by Dr. J.B. Frye for CBR. 181. No caption. 182. No caption. 183. No caption.
      Quintas Crespa 184. No caption. 185. Onions are a plentiful staple at the Quinta Crespo market in Caracas; the photo was taken to illustrate a study of the marketing of agricultural products in VE, prepared by Dr. George L. Mehren for CBR at the request of the Ministry of Agriculture. 186. This shows how blocks of the traditional VE white cheese are stored at the Quinta Crespo market in Caracas; the photo was taken to illustrate the study of marketing agricultural products in VE by Dr. George L. Mehren, arranged by CBR for the Ministry of Agriculture. 187. Close-up of the traditional and tasty - but dangerously unsanitary Venezuelan white cheese. The photo illustrates a study of marketing agricultural products in Venezuela, undertaken by Dr. George L. Mehren for CBR at the request of the Ministry of Agriculture. 188. This is a typical view of the Quinta Crespo market, taken to illustrate a CBR study of Venezuelan market structure by Dr. George L. Mehren. 189. Children line up to enter private school at El Tigrito, Anzoatequi state.
      Department of Irrigation 190. Canal de aduccin del embalse de Taiguaiguay, invadido por la maleza. 191. Limpia a mano de un canal secundario en el Proyecto de Suata. 192. Pequeo canal en el que la maleza ha sido segada a mano. En la foto pueden apreciarse tambin las estructuras para el control del agua en el Proyecto de Suata. 193. Tierra de primera clase situada en la zona del Proyecto de Guataparo, que no ha sido limpiada ni preparada el riego, a pesar de estar cuizada por un canal de regadio. 194. Tierra de primera clase y muy valiosa del Proyecto de Suata, que ha sido acondicionada para el riego. 195. Campo que se acondiciona para el reigo en el Proyecto de Suata. Slo en tierras planas puede hacerse una buena lavor de nivelacin. 196. Terreno excelente en el que el agua de riego no se ha controlado y solo ha servido para abrir zanjas profundas. 197. Camp recin deforestado y libre de malezas, listo para pasarle la niveladora. 198. Campo acondicionado para un riego eficiente. 199. He aqui un potrero que solo se ha limpiado parcialmente y que se riega dejando corer el agua sin ningn control. 200. Tierra de la misma calidad que la de la foto no. 10, debidamente acondicionada para el riego. [Number 10 is now number 194] 201. Este potreto, de gran capacidad de sustenacin, recibe el riego mientras el Ganado se retiene en un proyecto adyacente. 202. Plantacin de caa de azcar prcticamente perdida, a causa del excesivo crecimiento de malas hierbas, las cuales no pudieron controlarse por la imposibilidad de utilizar maquinaria sobre los lodazales formados. 203. Campo de cao de azcar contiguo al anterior, que puede cultivarse con maquinaria por haber sido nivelado y acondicionado para un riego eficiente. 204. Cuando la tierra est debidamente nivelada se evitan los lodazales y pueden utilizarse tractors para controlar las malas hierbas, con lo que se elimina la mayoria del trabajo a mano. 205. Canal de aduccin de Suata, limpiado parcialmente hace varios meses. 206. Canal de aduccin de Taiguaiguay, en el cual se est limpiando la vegetacin y los sedimentos. 207. Canal recin limpiado. Estos canales pueden limpiarse sin interrumpir el curso libre del agua por los mismos. 208. Campo el en que el agua acumulada en los luares bajos mat las plantas e impidi el cultivo. En este campo se pierde el 50% de la cosecha. 209. Campo de maiz, sin nivelacin apropiada, donde el agua acumulada en algunas secciones ha mermado la cosecha en un 20%. 210. Campo de maiz debidamente nivelado, que muestra una perfecta uniformidad en su cosecha, debido a que su superficie ha permitido un riego y un cultivo adecuados. 211. Cosecha perdida por falta de nivelacin de la tierra. 212. Tierra del mismo tipo que la de la foto anterior, acondicionada para el cultivo intensivo de hortalizas con regadio. 213. Las prcticas de cultivo intensivo dan rendimientos elevados cuando la tierra puede ser regada de una manera apropiada. 214. Esta tierra de primera clase, situada en Guataparo, tiene un canal que bordea la finca y, sin embargo, permanece sin desarrollar. 215. Esta finca de Taiguaiguay ha sido habilitada para el cultivo, pero no se ha nivelado. Su valor aumentaria considerablemente con una nivelacin adecuada. 216. Fincas de Suata cultivadas intensivamente. Esta tierra es de un valor muy elevado, y el gasto realizado en acondicionarla para el riego puede recupararse en uno o dos aos. 217. Esta es una tierra de buena calidad, situada en la parte inferior del Proyecto de Suata, la cual solamente produce pastos en manchas diseminadas, debido a la falta de drenaje. 218. Tierra falta de drenaje en el Proyecto de Suata, la cual tendria un also valor si fuese devidamente nivelada. 219. Campos muy productivos en el Proyecto de Suata, cuya tierra est convenientemente drenada y regada. 220. Compuertas de control en el lugar donde el canal de aduccin toma sus agues del rio Aragua. En la foto aparece tabien la casa del encargado. 221. Compuertas de control en el rio Aragua, en la cabecera del canal de aduccin. 222. Canal principal, a la salida del embalse de Taiguaiguay. 223. Represa de desviacin y compuerta principal, en el lugar donde el canal de aduccin desvia el agua del rio Aragua hacia el embalse. 224. Compuerta principal y canal de desviacin del Proyecto de Suata, para suministrar agua a los canales secundarios. 225. Ejemplo de estructuras y compuertas principales de control. 226. Vista del Embalse de Taiguaiguay, desde la estructura de desage. 227. He aqui otra vista del embalse, pudiendo observarse las represas al fondo. 228. Estructura del aliviadero, sin terminar. 229. Vista del embalse de Suata, desde la represa. 230. Desembocadura del canal de aduccin en el embalse. En esta zona hay una gran acumulacin de sedimentos. 231. Compuerta principal del canal de aduccin el embalse. 232. El agua ha socavado la base de los muros del canal de aduccin del embalse de Suata y se escapa por su parte inferior, como puede observarse en la foto. 233. Seccin de un canal secundario de concreto, en el Proyecto de Taiguaiguay, hundido y resquebrajado, debido a que el terreno se sent despues de haberse sometido al regadio. 234. Ejemplo de erosion de mrgenes en un canal del Proyecto de Guataparo. 235. Esta cosecha no justificaria el pago de ninguna contribucin por concepto de uso de agua. Con un riego adecuado, podrian producirse en esta tierra muy buenas cosechas. 236. Este comap ha sido preparado para pagar con holgura las contribuciones por el use del agua. 237. Campos que muestran cosechas exelentes, con las cuales podrian satisfacerse las contribuciones para el pago de los costos de operacin y mantenimiento, asi como los de construccin del proyecto. 238. Vista de la represa de Guataparo, tomada desde su parte inferior. 239. Parte superior de la represa de Guataparo. Obsrvese su tamao relativamente pequeo con relacin a la gran capacidad de almacenamiento de agua del embalse. 240. Vista del embalse. Este proyecto cuenta con un excelente abastecimiento de agua. 241. Canal de concreto. Este sistema de canales es costoso, pero despus de terminado, los costos de mantenimiento son bajos y su eficiencia para la distribucin del agua des elevada. 242. Aliviadero para proteccin del canal principal. 243. Escaln de caida del agua en un canal decundario, que sirve para reducer el declive del canal, con el fin de evitar la erosin. 244. En los pastos bajo riego puede mantenerse el Ganado vacuno durante la temporada en que los dems potreros estn secos. De esta manera, el crecimiento del ganado es continuo durante todo el ao. 245. El ganado vacuno lechero de alta calidad puede alimentarse con forraje verde cortado y mantenerse durante todo el ao en potreros con regadio. 246. Los pastos bien regados pueden ser un cultivo del mayor valor cuando se utilizan para alimentar ganado de buena calidad. 247. Finca con suelo de alta calidad, cuya cosecha se ha perdido por falta de un sistema apropiado de riego y drenaje. 248. Campo nivelado convenientemente para el riego y el drenaje, el cual puede ser trabajado eficientemente con maquinaria. 249. He aqu dos campos de caa de azcar, uno de 14 meses y otro de 3 meses. Con un riego apropiado se hace posible la recoleccin continua.
    - CBR, Miscellaneous, Training Album, Prints: 43 (Box 12, Folder 233)
      250. Many farm laborers working on the government land came out to tractor school. 251. CBR farm technicians instructed them in the fundamental of tractor driving. 252. Special emphasis was given to maintenance of equipment. 253. Many inexperienced farmers showed both interest and ability to learn quickly. 254. Construction is pushed ahead in Portuguesa State cattle country. 255. In an effort to beat the six months' period of heavy rains. 256. Young Venezuelans were trained to operate heavy machinery. 257. Andes road is opened to traffic, marking CBR experimental road as a success. 258. Work was started on road through cane and coffee country in Lara State. 259. New road will join main highway, opening way to market for many local farmers. 260. Unhealthful bedroom is changed 261. by cutting out window, painting walls, and employing home-made sheets. 262. Dark, unhealthful rural house 263. is enlarged by family into clean, airy home under CBR planning. 264. Encouraged by success of neighbors and CBR technicians' urgings 265. many families are rebuilding walls and adding 2 or 3 rooms to houses. 266. Chimneys were built on back of houses to relieve kitchens of smoke. 267. Carpentry classes show how to put boxes and other cheap materials to practical use. 268. Gardens at CBR centers build interest and provide training for family garden program. 269. Villagers meet in CBR centers to plan community campaigns. 270. Doctor discusses local health problems with villagers at CBR center. 271. Women learn to prepare new dishes with emphasis on nutritive value of foods. 272. Equipment and instruction in fruit and vegetable canning is available at centers. 273. CBR technician demonstrates meat curing process to village women. 274. Classes sometimes meet in rural homes to show best use of family kitchen. 275. Children eat together in miniature dinging rooms at stations. 276. Children brushing teeth before sitting down to eat. 277. Mothers prepare milk and cereal according to instructions of CBR technician. 278. Cafeteria style encourages children to wait upon themselves. 279. Mothers make simple baby beds from boxes. 280. Bed is ready for baby at modest farm home. 281. Rural kitchen is torn down and replaced 282. New room with built-in cement stove, table and cupboards. 283. Gardening equipment is made available to families by CBR. 284. Gardening parcels are distributed among young people at CBR center grounds. 285. In its work with rural families, CBR emphasizes such health measures 286. as the boiling of drinking water. 287. Family has dining room furniture for first time. 288. Family transforms cluttered room 289. Girls copied dressing tables and wardrobes from their homes. 290. CBR home technician shoes low cost beds made at center. 291. No caption. 292. Mattresses were made of excelsior and flour sacks.
    - CBR, Reports, Agricultural Extension Course at College of Agriculture, Maracay, Prints: 22 (Box 12, Folder 234)
      1. - 22. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, REports, Cooperative Activities of the CBR with the Practical School of Agriculture, Maracay, State of Aragua, Prints: 30 (Box 13, Folder 235)
      1. - 30. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Cooperative Activities of the CBR with the Training Center for Home Demonstration Agents at Maracay, State of Aragua, Prints: 27 (Box 13, Folder 236)
      1. - 27. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Cooperative Agricultural Extension and Field Training Activities of the CBR, Ministry of Agriculture, the National Agrarian Institute and the Agricultural Bank, State of Aragua, Venezuela, Prints: 29 (Box 13, Folder 237)
      1. - 29. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Ministerio de Agriculture y Cria, Centro de Entrenamiento de Tractoristas (Box 13, Folder 238)
      Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Regional Agricultural Resource Studies, Prints: 31 (Box 13, Folder 239)
      1. - 31. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Section I - CBR, Prints: 54 (Box 13, Folder 240)
      1. - 54. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Venezuela, Prints: 28 (Box 13, Folder 241)
      1. - 28. Captions included with photographs.
    - CBR, Reports, Venezuela 1951, Prints: 32 (Box 13, Folder 242)
      1. - 28. Captions included with photographs. 29. Dr. Loreto Arismendi addresses the luncheon group gathered in honor of Mr. Harrison (with cigar). Dr. Tamayo, Minister of Agriculture, is seated at Mr. Harrison's right. 30. Mr. Harrison and Dr. Bernardo Jofre, Public Relations director for AIA in Venezuela, in a post-luncheon demonstration of good feeling. 31. No caption. 32. No caption.
    - INLACA, Prints: 20 (Box 13, Folder 243)
      1. Mr. Lynne Blum, Superintendent of the INLACA plant of Valencia, makes the rounds to check on automatic milk fillers which turn out cartons at the rate of 35 per minute. 2. Flash pasteurizer installed in the INLACA plant at Valencia doubled to 35, 000 quarts daily the output capacity of the plant. 3. E.G. Van Wagner (center), General Manager of the VBEC, founded by Nelson A. Rockefeller and his brothers, says farewell to Edward Kimball (left), resigning manager of VBEC's successful pasteurized milk company, INLACA and good luck to Prudencio Moure (right), the new manager. Both Kimball and Moure are from Florida. 4. Venezuelan youngster grasps new safeguard for his health. The sanitary paper milk carton, introduced to VE by INLACA, is automatically sealed with paraffin, protecting children against the practice of dilution of milk in interval between plant and consumer. By lending technical assistance to dairy farmers, providing them with a steady, year-round market for their produce, and setting up an effective milk distribution system, INLACA is attempting to increase milk production and consumption in VE, thus bringing larger quantities of this basic food into the diets of the people and lowering infant mortality rates. 5. As part of Nutrition Week in the state of Carabobo, the Superintendent of Education, district supervisors and the CIDEA representative in Carabobo carried out programs relative to Nutrition Education. INLACA cooperated in the nutrition education programs by supplying, through the CIDEA representative, a sufficient amount of milk for all schools in Valencia, Flor Amarilla and Los Guayos. In the above picture, masks of CARALIN, the Leche Carabobo cow, were distributed to school children along with milk. 6. As part of Nutrition Week in the state of Carabobo, the Superintendent of Education, district supervisors and the CIDEA representative in Carabobo carried out programs relative to Nutrition Education. INLACA cooperated in the nutrition education programs by supplying, through the CIDEA representative, a sufficient amount of milk for all schools in Valencia, Flor Amarilla and Los Guayos. In the above picture, masks of CARALIN, the Leche Carabobo cow, were distributed to school children along with milk. 7. As part of Nutrition Weed in the state of Carabobo, the Superintendent of Education, district supervisors and the CIDEA representative in Carabobo carried out programs relative to Nutrition Education. INLACA cooperated in the nutrition education programs by supplying, through the CIDEA representative, a sufficient amount of milk for all schools in Valencia, Flor Amarilla and Los Guayos. In the above picture, masks of CARALIN, the Leche Carabobo cow, were distributed to school children along with milk. 8. Business got too bigso VBEC remodeled the old INLACA milk pasteurizing plant in Valencia, state of Carabobo, more than doubling the floor space and turning this handsome new faade to busy Avenida Michelena. 9. Watch the Milk Go Around! These complicated machines do everything but drink the milk, and of course that's the one thing everyone wants to do for himself. They assemble the carton, coat it with paraffin, fill it with pasteurized milk direct from the cooling chamber, then seal the carton. Visitors to the INLACA plant in Valencia, capital of the state of Carabobo, can watch the milk make this fascinating trip in a matter of minutes and then take a carton home, secure in the sanitation of handling the pasteurized product. Also, the date on which the milk is packaged is stamped on the container. 10. Inside view of the market. 11. A view of the store, the sign is not yet up but will go on the side white wall. 12. The plantain, a staple Venezuelan food, receives special attention in a nutrition display. 13. CIDEA posters advise growing vegetables for health and economy and flowers for enjoyment, in cooperation with an "arbor day" observed in Caracas. 14. A teacher explains to children in a school nutrition club, sponsored by CIDEA, the differences between leafy and root vegetables. 15. A traveling CIDEA instructor explains posters showing the relation of good diet to good health. 16. No caption. 17. No caption. 18. Venezuela was the first South American country to adopt the sanitary, economical packaging of milk in cartons rather than bottles. 19. INLACA milkman makes a delivery to a thatched roof home in Valencia. Many of the districts reached by INLACA formerly had success only with raw milk. 20. The success of the INLACA plant, which recently was enlarged, had caused dairy herds in the neighborhood to increase by more than 50 per cent.
    - MILDOSA, Prints: 3 (Box 13, Folder 244)